<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on The Anthropeneur</title><link>https://anthropeneur.com/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on The Anthropeneur</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anthropeneur.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Anthropeneur</title><link>https://anthropeneur.com/p/what-is-anthropeneur/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://anthropeneur.com/p/what-is-anthropeneur/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anthropeneur = anthrop + entrepeneur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anthrop is a Greek root meaning &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo;, entrepreneur is an individual who creates a new business, bearing most of the risks and enjoying most of the rewards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People are central to everyone life. All the things we do orbit directly or indirectly around people. And we would be nothing without people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With people I mean our beloved ones, our parents, our family, our friends, but also unknown people, strangers, acquaintances. Indeed, before becoming so, friends were strangers. And so any stranger is just a stranger in this moment of time, but any stranger can become a friend. even a really close friend, in the future, even abruptly and rapidly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So people constitute the essence of our life. They are the most precious resource. And all other resources are only secondary, attached to the resources of people. Money means nothing if there is no one with whom to share them, a big house would be worthless and sad if it is empty, a big achievement would not seem so big if it is not celebrated with someone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Happiness is true only when shared&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having recognized that people are the most important&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This need appears to be and I guess will be even more urgent now when we are living in the era of AI, when the chances to feel alienated, isolated, excluded, relegated will be higher than ever. In this era we have already started to loose contanct with other humans. And this looseness is fostered by the technologies that replicates essentially that human connections. All the recent technological advancements and breakthrough, if looked deeply, are essentially ways to replicate and, as it is stated, expand the human connection. Social networks are born to expand our connections and to remain in touch even in distance. AI tries to replicate human behaviors, in the way it thinks, speaks, and acts, even though I could have infinitely many ways to do so. Similarly, robots resemble humans.
But the risk behind these technological advancements is that rather than expanding the human connections, they impoverish them and substitute them with surrogates of the human experiences. As a consequence, in this period of time people are more lonely, anxious, depressed than ever, values are lost because people feel disconnected and aimless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering all of these, why we lose focus on the importance of people in our life? Why it is not spoken openly that all what we do is worthless without other people, that our success is aided if not dictated by other people, that our meaning of life is filled by people and our lives improves drastically if we lean openly towards other people, if our actions directly or indirectly help other people. Why shall we let this basilar and primary truth of the human experience slip inexorably to our unconsciousness? Why we do not realize that most of the problems of our society stems from this lack of consciousness?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this aknowledgement, with this blog I commit to document what I come across and the experience in this exploration of the human nature, with the goal to learn what I can emiliorate (and hopefully whoever reads this) the roots that connect me with other humans.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>